Guide to the Brooklyn letterhead collection BCMS.0008
Brooklyn Collection
- Olcott, C., Dr., 1873
  Doctor. 104 Bedford Ave., cor. Rodney St.
- Old Mill Mardi Gras Association, 1910
  Social association. Foot of Crescent Street
- Old Mill Yacht Club, 1931
  Social club. Foot of Crescent Street
- Old Staten Island Dyeing Establishment, The, 1892
  Dyeing company. 491 Fulton Street
- Oliver, John S., 1878, 1881
  Hardware dealer. 537, 543 Myrtle Avenue
- Olsen, Harry, 1928
  Painter and decorator. 7112 8th Avenue
- Opp, John, 1879, 1880, 1882, 1884, 1887
  Stoves and heater dealer. 489 Myrtle Avenue
- Opper, H., 1889
  Metal worker. 41 Atlantic Street
- Ormiston, Robert, 1890
  Mason and plasterer. 673 DeKalb Avenue, near Marcy Ave.
- Orthodox Jewish Congregation of Coney Island, 1944
  Synagogue. 2916 West 25th Street
- Ortiz, John W.S., 1882, 1886
  House and sign painter. 340, 343 Myrtle Ave., cor./near Carlton
- Osborn, M., 1890
  Awning maker. 344-1/2 13th Street
- Osborne, Samuel's Sons, 1880
  Saw mill. Corner of Columbia and Baltic Streets
- Osias, Harry L., 1949
  Building construction. 130 Clinton Street
- Otis Elevator Company, 1929
  Elevator installation. 130 Clinton St.
- Ott & Company, 1896
  Stone yard. Bath and 15th Avenues
- Ouchterloney & Tandy, 1885
  Granite and marble works. 5th Ave. 24th and 25th Sts.
- Outwater & Saxtan, 1864
  Iron railings maker. 279 Adams Street
- Outwater, Jacob, 1873, 1878
  Iron railings maker. 339 Adams Street
- Outwater, John F., 1885
  Iron railings maker. 78 Smith Street
- Overland Tea House, 1891
  Grocer. NE cor. Bedford Ave. and South 9th St.
- Ovington Brothers, 1880
  China importers. 246-252 Fulton Street
- Owens, Arthur J., 1881
  Merchant tailor. 512 Court Street near Nelson
- Owens, L.W., 1898
  Undertaker and embalmer. 1412 Fulton Street, near Brooklyn Avenue
- Oxley, John A. & Co., 1868
  Brewery. Union Brewery, 23-27 Union Street
- Packard, Edwin, 1897
  Realtor [?]. 38 and 40 Clinton Street
- Packard Motor Car Company of New York, 1995
  Car manufacturers. Flatbush and Eighth Avenue
- Packer Collegiate Institute, 1871
  School. Joralemon Street
- Paddock Cork Co., The, 1897
  Cork maker. 21 and 23 Dodworth Street
- Palmer, George, 1869, 1870, 1872
  Stoves dealer. 200 Franklin Street, bet. Huron and India
- Palmer, George, 1880
  Plumber. 63 Green Point Avenue, near Franklin St.
- Palmer, L.N., Dr., 1868
  Doctor. 71 Fourth Street
- Palmer, Wm. B., 1868
  Hat maker. 35 Fourth Street
- Palmer, Wm. H., 1878
  Fishing tackle maker. 18 Tillary St. [formerly 24 Hicks St.]
- Palmer's Dock, 1897
  Railroad station, Lehigh Valley Railroad Co. No. 9th St. and Kent Ave. station
- Pape, Frederick, 1900
  Bookbinder. 34 Melrose Street
- Pape, George, 1868
  Metal ware. 110 Fulton Avenue, near Hoyt St.
- Pape & Rempel, 1899
  Greengrocer. 1014 Wallabout Market
- Par Lumber Company, 1944
  Lumber dealer. 2101-2127 Neptune Avenue
- Paret, John & Co., 1880
  Clothier. 402 & 404 Fulton St.
- Parfitt Bros., 1882, 1901
  Architects. Phenix Building, 16 Court Street; 26 Court St
- Park Bros. / William C. Park, 1885, 1889, 1890
  Painters and paper hangers. 277 Court St. [formerly 314 Degraw St., near Court], bet. Butler and Douglass
- Park, James H., 1865-1866
  Seedsman and florist. 145 to 151 Court St., cor. State
- Park, Edward C., 1883
  Printer and paper hanger. 94 Atlantic Street
- Parker, 1894
  Robes. 70 Fort Greene Place
- Parker, Geo. & Co., 1879
  Shoe dealers. 579 Fulton Street
- Parker, John T. ('s Son), 1865, 1883
  Undertaker. 135 Union Avenue, cor. of Hope St./N. 1st St
- Parkside Memorial Chapels
  Funeral home. 1700 Coney Island Ave.
- Parr, F.J., 1887, 1898
  Horseshoer. 316 Rockaway Ave. near Prospect Place
- Parsons, Henry W., 1865
  Plumber. 8 Myrtle Avenue
- Pasfield, G. & C., 1883
  Builders and hardware. 239 Broadway, bet. 7th and 8th
- Pashley, H., 1869, 1870, 1875
  Carpenter and builder. 162 South 6th Street/Cor. South 9th and 8th Streets
- Parsons & Ketcham, 1870
  Plumbers. 5 Myrtle Avenue
- Pastarnack & Son, 1907-1908
  Metal worker. 1067 Myrtle Avenue bet. Sumner and Lewis
- Paterson, John, 1872
  Plumber. 407 Myrtle Avenue
- Paterson, John, 1893
  Plumber. 1204 Fulton St., near Bedford Ave.
- Patrons' Paint Works, circa late 1800s-1906
  Paint makers. 241-243 Plymouth St.
- Patten, Jefferson Jr. & Co., 1882
  Wrought iron pipe dealer. 59 & 61 Greenpoint Avenue
- Patterson, Wm. H., 1910
  Ship joiner and cabinet maker. 397 Third Street
- Paul, Charles B., 1896
  Steel files. 467 Keap Street
- Payne, Robert, 1883, 1890
  Carpenter and builder. 340 Willoughby Avenue
- Payne, W., 1889
  Carpet upholsterer. 12 Halsey Street
- Peace, Harvey W. Co., 1890-1891
  Saw and tool works. 469 Keap Street
- Peace, W.C. & Co., 1882
  General hardware dealers. C. Tenney, successor. 178 Conselyea Street
- Pearce, Uriah, 1875
  Shoe store. 579 Fulton Avenue
- Pearl Hand Laundry, 1899
- Pearson, A.'s Sons, 1903
  Furniture and carpets. 59, 61 and 63 Myrtle Avenue
- Pearson, Andrew & Co., 1896
  Decorators. 326 Flatbush Ave. bet. 7th and 8th
- Pearson, James, 1884
  Carpenter and builder. 143 Clermont Avenue, near Myrtle
- Pease & Poillon, 1879
  Lumber dealer. SE cor. Bond and Third Sts.
- Peck & Elhardt, 1931
  Stamp dealer [?]. 181 Jewell St.
- Peck [Moyer] & Vogt, 1889
  Locksmiths. 346 Myrtle Avenue
- Peck & Yates, 1898
  Painters. 431 Bedford Avenue
- Pedersen & Knudsen, 1926
  Carpenters and builders. 465 53rd Street
- Peerless Custom Laundry, 1950
  Laundry. 180 7th Avenue
- Peerless Paper Co., 1942
  Paper dealer. 532-536 St. Mark's Avenue
- Peirce, C.H., 1880
  Hay and grain dealer. 560 & 562 Myrtle Avenue cor. Schenk St.
- Pelletreau, John E., 1879
  Plumber. 84 Elliott Place
- Pelly Dry Dock Co., 1907
  Dry docks. foot 25th, 26th, 27th Sts.
- Pendlington, James, 1879, 1881
  Shipsmith. Elizabeth St., Erie Basin, and foot Court St.
- Peoples Gas Light Company of Brooklyn, The, 1892
  Gas company. 419 Myrtle Avenue, near Clinton
- Peoples Trust Company, The, 1900
  Bank
- Peoples Surety Company, 1909
  Insurance. 176 Montague Street
- Perkins & Green, 1881, 1884, 1889
  Carpenters and builders. 264 Degraw Street, near Clinton
- Perkins, H.D., 1879
  Painter. 368 Navy Street
- Perry, John C., 1880
  Attorney. 346 Fulton Street
- Perry, A.J., 1884
  House Painter
- Peter, J., 1905, 1909, 1910
  Hardware dealer. 993 Myrtle Ave. bet. Sumner and Throop; 983 Myrtle near Throop
- Peter, J. George, 1900
  Dry goods dealer. 204 Graham Avenue
- Peters, Rody, 1881, 1886
  Horseshoer. Cor. Park and Waverly Avenues
- Peters, John, 1898
  Horseshoer. 13 Bergen Street, near Court
- Peters, John, 1904
  Grocer. 1039 Myrtle Ave., cor. Sumner; 1261 Myrtle and 1409 Myrtle
- Petersen, Necolai T., 1901
  Metal worker and stove repair. 84th Street, bet. 16th and 17th
- Peterson, F., 1872
  Grain, hay dealer. 64 Front Street
- Peterson, O.F., 1935
  Real estate. 6th Ave. at 3rd Street
- Peterson, S.A., 1892
  Cornice and skylight works. 290 & 292 Hooper St.
- Peth, George, 1898
  Undertaker and stables. 123-127 Boerum Street
- Pettit, D.S., Mrs., 1870
  Dressmaker. 55 Pineapple Street
- Pfeiffer & Co., 1898
  Plumber and gas fitter. 2462 Eastern Parkway, near Essex
- Pfeiffer, Martin, 1904
  Plumber and gas fitter. 2454 Pitkin Avenue, near Linwood
- Phaelon, Wm., 1885
  Carpenter and builder. 502 Smith Street, near Garnet
- Phelps, R.G. & Co., 1878
  Lumber merchant. Kent Avenue, cor. Hewes Street
- Phenix Insurance Company of Brooklyn, 1862, 1865, 1873, 1879, 1886
  345 Fulton St.; 1 Court St.; 12 & 14 Court Street
- Phillips, Doup, & Company, 1888, 1891
  Heating & heating supplies. 1 to 13 Adams Street
- Phillips & Ferguson, 1878
  Whiting maker. 60 Beekman St. (removed to 48 Beekman St.)
- Phillips, John V., 1888
  Florist. 82 Montague Street
- Phraner, William, 1879
  Jobbing mason. 573 Fulton Street
- Picardy Mills, Inc., 1930
  Gloves and underwear maker. 241 Boerum Street
- Pickard, Thos. J., 1892
  Sign maker. 163-165 Lorimer Street
- Pickard, William A., 1890
  Painters' supplies. 533-1/2 Grand Street
- Picoli, L. & Sons, 1893
  Painter. 822 DeKalb Avenue bet Throop & Tompkins
- Pidgeon & Bennett, 1877
  Carpenters and builders. 247 Nostrand Ave., near Lafayette Avenue
- Pieper, E., 1909
  Plumber and gas fitter. 105 Third Avenue
- Pierrepont, H.B., Estate of, 1854
  Private estate
- Pierrepont House, D.P. Peters, 1867
  Hotel. Cor. Montague and Hicks Sts.
- Pierrepont Street Baptist Church, Trustees of the, 1865
- Pierson, Chas. L., 1898
  Carpenter and builder. 455 Carlton Avenue
- Piesch, Wm. A.A., 1894
  Electrical engineer and contractor. 102 Ellery Street near Marcy Avenue
- Pike, I.E., 1881
  Men's furnishings. 224 Court Street
- Pike & Vincent, 1881
  Carpenters and builders. 148 Third Avenue, near Warren St.
- Pilgrim Steam Laundry, The, 1896
  92 Third Street
- Pink, William H., 1903
  Real estate and insurance. 738 Madison Street
- Pinner, I., 1872
  Furniture maker. 83 Fulton Street
- Pinner, L., 1886
  Furniture maker. 929 Fulton Street, near Waverley Ave.
- Pinsker, Wm. Company, 1938
  Paper distributor. 2917-2921 West 15th Street
- Pioneer Iron Works, 1874, 1880
  Iron works. 149 to 163 William Street
- Pipe, George W., 1886
  Carpenter and builder. 42 Albany Avenue
- Pitbladdo, Thomas, 1865, 1868, 1894
  Marble monument maker. 5th Avenue, cor. 24th (Greenwood Cemetery)
- Pitt, John B. (& Son), 1869
  Furniture dealer. 112-118 Jay St., near Sands
- Pitt, Thomas, 1875, 1876, 1883
  Plumber. 69 6th Avenue, bet. Bergen St. & Flatbush Ave.
- Pitt, William, 1880
  Plumber. 235 Flatbush Avenue bet Dean & Bergen
- Pittsburgh Plate Glass Co., 1914
  Glass dealer. Cor. Third Avenue & Dean Street
- Place, Charles, 1875
  Livery stable. 101 to 107 South 6th Street, near Fourth
- Plaza Boarding, Livery & Sales Stables, The, 1876
  Stables. 431 Flatbush Ave. near Park Place
- Poiale, Joe, 1897
  Bottle dealer. 125 Withers Street
- Poillon, C. & R., 1881
  Blacksmith shop. foot of Bridge Street
- Poillon, C. & R., 1888
  Shipbuilder. 224 South Street
- Pollard, Joseph G., 1880
  Tool maker. 141 Raymond Street
- Pool, Geo. & Sons (Inc.) / Geo. Pool's Sons, 1871, 1879, 1888, 1889, 1897, 1927
  Oil and lamp dealer. 70 and 72 Fulton Street
- Poole & Clothier, 1870
  Painters and paper hangers. 5 Clinton Street and 99 Sands Street
- Poole, John W., M.D., 1903
  Doctor. Voorhies Avenue
- Porter, J.V., 1883-1884
  Carpenter and builder. 115 & 117 Prospect Place, near Flatbush
- Post Gas Range & Repair Service, 1944
  Gas range sales. 2935 West 28th Street
- Post, Philip Jr., 1890
  Plumber and gas fitter. 1956 Fulton Street
- Potavin & Stryker, 1879
  Masons and builders. 757 Madison Street
- Potter, Benjamin, 1876
  House furnishings. 295 Grand Street, cor. of 8th
- Potter, F.W., 1873
  Decorator and painter. 1122 Fulton Street, near Franklin Avenue
- Potter, T.B., 1898
  Carriage maker. 17 and 19 Dean Street
- Pouch, Frank & Son, 1871
  Carpenter and builder. 253 Adams Street
- Powell, Robert I., 1865, 1866, 1869
- Powell, Samuel S., 1869
  Clothing. 118 Fulton Street
- Powell & Vining, 1860
  Metal worker. 104 Fulton Street and 7 Henry Street
- Power, James M., 1936
  Realtor. 185 Montague Street
- Powers, James, 1893
  Carpenter and builder. 818 Atlantic Avenue
- Powers, P.H., 1880
  Livery stable. 417 & 419 Court Street
- Poynter, T., 1881
  Nurseryman and florist. 668 Fulton Avenue, cor. Elliott Place
- Practical Electro-Plating Works, 1904
  11 and 13 McKibbin Street, near Broadway
- Pratt Institute, 1891
- Prendergast, P., 1883
  Mason and plasterer. 81 Atlantic Avenue
- Prentice & Co., 1880
  Storage facility. Wall Street Ferry
- Prentice, James H., 1864
  Auctioneer
- Prescot, S.C., 1893
  Carpenter and builder
- Prescott, M., 1879
  Lamp and oils dealer. 127 Grand Street
- Prescott, Thomas, 1878
  Butcher. Stall 32, Atlantic Market (removed to 115 Atlantic St., 3rd door below Henry)
- Price, A., 1899
  Stationer. 75 Graham Avenue
- Prince, John D.'s Sons, 1871
  Paint dealer. 23 Fulton Street
- Printy, James, 1909
  The Old Phoenix Iron Works. 293 Degraw Street, near Court
- Prosser, J., 1882
  Carpenter and builder. 617 Baltic Street
- Protzmann, Wm., 1891
  Decorator and paper hanger
- Pulcifer, A.H., 1869
  Metal work and ware. 120 Fulton Avenue
- Pulcifer & Bradley, 1870, 1873
  Stove maker. 128, 472 Fulton Avenue, cor. Elm Place
- Pullman, John, 1891, 1893
  Real estate. 741 Union Street, cor. 5th Avenue
- Pulmosan Safety Equipment Corp., 1927
  Safety equipment distributor. 386 Jay Street
- Purcell, Benj. T., 1896, 1900
  Plumber. 66th St., near 5th Ave.; shop: 74th St. & 3rd Ave.
- Purcell, Thomas, Capt., 1878
  Towing. Propeller Niagara. 78 Dupont Street
- Putnam, Hiram A., 1871
  Mason and builder. 100 Adelphi Street [formerly 70 Adelphi]
- Putnam, W.A., 1921
  Portrait painter [?]. 70 Willow Street
- Pyle, Cyrus, 1869
  Chemist. Fulton, cor. Pierrepont & Columbia, cor. Carroll
- Quabach, Theo., 1877
  Baker and confectioner. 455 Court St., near 4th Place
- Quattlander, John, 1893
  Carpenter and builder. 192 Clymer Street
- Quevedo, John / Quevedo & Smith, 1885-1886
  Painter(s). Sumner Avenue near Fulton St.; 1623 Fulton Street
- Quick, H.H., 1903, 1910
  Plumber. 579 DeKalb Avenue
- Quick, Louis E., 1897
  Plumber. Avenue C and Flatbush Avenue
- Quimby, David S. (& Son), 1859, 1860, 1865, 1867-1869, 1874, 1878
  Range and grate factory. 4, 8 Henry St. cor. Poplar near Fulton
- Quimby, David S. Jr., 1891-1892
  Auctioneer and real estate broker, insurance. 208 Montague Street, near Court
- Quin, John, 1861
  Tailoring and clothing. 637 Myrtle Avenue
- Quinn, T.E., 1884
  Paper hanger. 562 Fulton St., near Music Hall
- Rabb Iron Works Co., 1908
  Engineers, machinists and boiler makers. Foot 26th and 27th Sts.
- Rabinowitz, Isidore, 1942
  Stationery. 1562 43rd Street
- Race, James H., 1881
  Dentist. 366 Clinton Street
- Rae, William P. Company, 1895, 1897
  Real estate. 394 Gates Avenue cor. Nostrand; 189-191 Montague St.
- Raine, T.C. Jr., 1891, 1895
  House and sign painter. 570, 572 Atlantic Avenue
- Randall-Donaldson Cadillac Corporation, 1936
  Car company [dealership?]. 749 Atlantic Avenue
- Randolph, J. & Sons, 1888
  315 Court Street, bet. Degraw and Sackett
- Randolph, John & Sons, 1880, 1882, 1883
  Paint and oil dealer. 281 Court St.; 285 Court St., cor. Douglass
- Rankin's Depot, 1868
  Wood, doors, sashes dealer. 95 Grand Street
- Ransom Bros., Inc., 1961
  Movers. 1470-2 Schenectady Ave.
- Rapoport, A., 1915
  Plumber. 329 Saratoga Avenue near Bergen St.
- Rauch's Cut Rate, 1930
  5-10 and Up Store. 55-50 Myrtle Avenue
- Rawson, J. (& T.), 1873, 1887
  Mason and builder. 173, 219 Clymer Street
- Ray, Forder / Daisley & Co., 1872, 1878, 1896
  Stoves and furnaces, makers and dealers. 61 Fulton Street
- Ray, M.B. & R. / Ray Brothers / Ray & Oakes, 1870, 1871, 1873, 1874, 1884
  Parlor, hall stoves, and ovens dealer. 375, 377, 417 Myrtle Avenue, near Clermont
- Raymond, F., 1885
  Carpenter and builder. 158 Henry Street, near Pierrepont
- Raynor, P.A., 1867
  Baker. 57 4th St., cor. South 6th
- Read, John H., 1885
  Sanitary plumber. 156 Gates Avenue
- Read, Thomas & Co., 1867-1868
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 85 Fulton Avenue bet. Bridge and Lawrence
- Ready, John, 1890
  Stone cutter. Grant Street
- Recht, C., 1887
  Hardware and metals dealer. 118 Grand Street
- Redmond Bros., 1894
  Real estate. 613 Vanderbilt Avenue
- Reeber, J. & Co., 1882
  Lumber dealer. 395-403 Broadway
- Reed, Chas. C. & Co. (formerly Turner & Co.), 1890
  Varnish maker. 112 East 14th Street opp. Academy of Music
- Reed, M., Mrs., 1877
  Milliner. 485 Fulton Street
- Reed, N.F. & Co., 1884
  Shoe store. 545 Fulton St.
- Rees & Lang, 1891
  Marble monument maker. 119-123 Noll Street, bet. Hamburg and Central Aves.
- Reeve, T. (& Son), 1867, 1869
  Builders. 48 & 50 Schermerhorn Street
- Reeves & Church, 1878
  Box maker. 127-135 Green Street, bet Franklin St. and Union Ave.
- Regan,John, 1899
  Horseshoer. 13 Kossuth Place
- Reid, Barnard, 1876, 1887
  Plumber. 559 Myrtle Ave., near Classon
- Reid, Hugh, 1880, 1884
  Plumber. 113 Flatbush Avenue
- Reid & Lally, 1868
  Plumbers. 100 Flatbush Avenue
- Reid, P. & Son, 1867
  Florists. Successors to Walter Park. Amity St., cor. of Clinton
- Reid's Union Dairy
  Dairy. 524-530 Waverly Avenue
- Reilly, John, 1886
  Stone mason. 105-1/2 Rogers Avenue
- Reiners, H. & H., 1897
  Distillers and distributors. 177 to 197 Stagg St.
- Reis, John Company, 1936
  Real estate. 787 Flatbush Avenue
- Reis, John & Co., circa late 1800s
  Real estate. 5 Willoughby Street
- Reizenstein, L., 1896
  Real estate and builder. 136A Sumner Avenue
- Reliable Bus Terminal, Inc., circa early 1900s
  Charter buses. 1377 East New York Ave.
- Reliance Architectural Iron Works, 1893
  W.A. Webb, J.E. Sears, O.J. Bloss. 243-247 Monitor St., 244-248 North Henry St.
- Rempel, J. & Co., 1900
  Fruits and produce dealer. 104 & 106 West Avenue
- Remsen, Burroughs & Co., 1869
  Mason's materials dealers. Yard, Cross' Dock, one block south of Division Ave.
- Remsen's Stables, 1877
  Stables. 344 Cumberland Street, near Fulton
- Remson, I.S. Manufacturing Co., The, 1894,1900
  Harness and horse goods. 740-750 Grand Street
- Rendt, Louis, 1879
  Wharfage. 420 Hamilton Avenue
- Rensch, C., 1868
  Dress and cloak maker. 180 Atlantic Street
- Rescue, Towing by Propeller, 1879
  Capt. J. Sheahan. 127 12th St., Gowanus
- Reservaline Manufacturing Co., The, 1910
  Preservaline makers. 854-864 Lorimer Street
- Resseguie, R. & Co., 1866
  Lumber mill. Kent Ave. cor. Hewes St.
- Reynolds, C.H. & Sons, 1891, 1893
  Coal and wood dealer. Morgan Ave., Meserole & Scholes St.; Grand St. & Newtown Creek; Rodney, cor. South 1st
- Reynolds, Isaac & Co., 1897
  Plumbing, gas fitting, metal work. 124 Broadway
- Rhatigan, James A. Co., 1937
  Licensed scavengers; cesspool builders. 4515 Avenue N; 1602 E. 56th St.
- Rhatigan, James A. Company, Inc., 1940
  Contractor and cesspool builder. 1602 East 56th Street and Avenue O
- Rhind, C., Mrs., 1889
  Milliner. 310 Fulton Street
- Rhinehart, Clark D., 1886
  Judge. 180 Grand St.
- Rice, John, 1903
  Plumber and steam fitter. 365 Halsey Street
- Rich, H. & G.W., 1879
  Grocers. 620 Third Avenue
- Thomas Richards (& Sons), 1886, 1889, 1896, 1902
  Painter and interior decorator. 1363 Fulton St.
- Richardson, E.W., 1880
  Tailor. Successor to Wm. Evans & Son. 156 Atlantic, cor. Clinton
- Richardson, H.C., 1872, 1882
  Hardware dealer. 59 & 61 Grand St. & 275 2nd St.
- Richter & Kaiser, 1941
  Real estate and insurance. 186 Remsen St.
- Ridgewood Chamber of Commerce Inc., 1939
  Business association. Ridgewood Times Building, Cypress & Myrtle Aves.
- Ridgewood Ice Co., 1879
  Ice distributor. Cor. Flushing and Waverly Avenues
- Ridgewood Lumber Co., 1933
  Lumber dealer. 1310 Myrtle Avenue
- Ridgewood Times, 1927, 1934
  Newspaper. Cypress and Myrtle Avenues
- Riedel, H., 1940
  Candy company. 3111 Glenwood Road
- Rigney & Company, 1917
  Confectioners. 348-354 Park Ave.; 68-72 Emerson Pl.; 65 Steuben St.
- Riker, Robert, 1867
  Undertaker. 56 Flatbush Avenue
- Rilatt & Parker, 1890, 1899, 1901
  Stair builder and cabinet maker. 58th St. and 13th Ave.
- Riley Bros., The, 1902
  Marble and granite works. Calvery Cemetery, opp. Penny Bridge entrance
- Riley & Cowley, 1895, 1901
  Machinists and engineers. Richards St., cor. Bowne St., near Atlantic dock
- Riley, Geo. T., 1890
  Caterer and confectioner. 751 & 753 Fulton St.; 282 Flatbush Ave.
- Riley, P., 1896
  Mason. 1754 Fulton Street
- Ring, Chas. E.
  Blacksmith. Cor. Kent Ave. & So. 6th St.
- Ris & Minor, 1881, 1883
  Painters. 327, 333 Court Street, near Sackett
- Rissler, Chas., 1891
  Carpenter and builder. Shop, cor. Gates & Irving Avenues
- Robb, James, 1874
  House and sign painter. 443 Broadway
- Robertson, William, 1869, 1878
  Horses and carriages to let. 67, 118 State Street
- Robinett, Thomas, 1872
  Carpenter and builder. 405 Kent Avenue
- Robins, Charles, 1870, 1871, 1886
  Plumber and gas fitter. 1 Gates Avenue; 1361 Fulton Street
- Robins & Gibson, 1864-1865
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 431 Fulton Avenue
- Robinson, J.P. & G.C., 1880-1881
  Robinson's Congress St. Stores
- Robinson, Morris, 1890
  Glass dealer. 210 Devoe Street
- Roche, Wm. J., 1875
  Plumber and gas fitter. 65 Henry Street
- Rockland-Rockport Lime Co., 1911
  Broadway, 5th Ave. and 23rd St.
- Rockliff, Charles, 1891
  Hay dealer. Cor. East and Flushing Aves., Wallabout Market, and Palmer's Dock
- Rockwood & Co., 1930
  Cocoa and chocolate. Washington Park and Waverly Aves.
- Rockwood, E.P., 1864
  Flour and grain dealer. 18 Myrtle Avenue, cor. Adams Street
- Rode, Charles, 1868
  Looking glass dealer. 162 Grand Street
- Rode & Horn Lumber Co., Inc., 1931
  Lumber dealer. 9 Lynch Street
- Rodwell, James, 1873, 1876
  Mason and builder. 21 So. 7th Street; 40 5th St.
- Roebling, John A.'s Sons Co., 1895
  117 & 119 Liberty Street
- Roebling Street Quick Service Garage, Inc., 1917
  Service station and garage. Corner Boradway and So. 8th St.
- Roebuck Bros., 1869
  Manufacturers and patenters. 58 Fulton Street
- Roehn, Hugo, 1890
  Leather goods maker. 350 North Second Street
- Roemmele, F. & Son, 1888
  Undertaker. 522 North 2nd St.
- Rogers, Peet & Co., 1878
  Clothiers. 402 & 404 Fulton St.
- Rogers, Thos. H., 1880
  Mason and builder. 475 Fifth Ave., cor. 11th St.
- Rohrs, August, 1908
  Grocer and butcher. 717 Third Avenue, cor. 23rd St.
- Roman-Aetna Blacking Corp., 1930
  Blacking dealer. 9 Fulton Street
- Romano Bros., 1920
  Fruit and vegetable dealer. 5724 Eighth Ave.
- Rooney & Morgan, 1891
  Dry dock and railway. Foot of India Street
- Roosevelt Savings Bank, 1934
  Bank. Gates Avenue and Broadway
- Rope & Co., 1891
  Lumber dealers. Cor. Kent Ave. and Hewes Street
- Rorvig, Herman, 1948
  General contractor. 1725 East 23rd Street
- Rose, Charles, 1894
  Butcher. 255 and 257 Fifth Avenue
- Rosebud Shop, The
  Ladies boutique. 786 Nostrand Avenue
- Rosenfeld, S. & Rosenhaft, 1907
  Theodore M. Roche, receiver. Iron workers. 249 Belmont Ave.
- Rosenthal, D., 1944
  Contractor. 2507 Mermaid Avenue
- Ross, David, 1873
  Dry goods dealer. 567 DeKalb Avenue
- Ross, G. & Sons, 1871, 1878, 1880
  Lumber dealer. Cor. Nevins & Butler Sts.
- Ross, Jay W.
  Printer. 321 Atlantic Ave., near Smith St.
- Ross, Robert, 1887
  Clothing store. 619 Myrtle Avenue
- Ross & Scanlan, 1876
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 331 Court Street, near Sackett Street
- Ross & Snyder, 1897, 1901
  Lumber dealers. Union St. and Third Ave.
- Ross, Sylvester, 1891
  Lumber dealer. Northwest cor. Columbia and Harrison Sts.
- Rossi, G., 1898
  Painter's supplies. 91 Hamilton Avenue
- Roth, George, 1913
  Butcher. 80 Montague Street
- Rothschild, J., 1885
  Milliner. 269 & 271 Fulton Street
- Roto Salt Company, 1910
  Salt dealer. 23 Flatbush Avenue
- Rowland, John H. & Son, 1892, 1898
  Stables. 460 & 462 DeKalb Avenue, cor. Kent; Lafayette and Waverly Aves.
- Royal Arcanum, 1950
  Fraternal society. 96 Sixth Avenue
- Royal Insurance Co., 1885, 1886, 1892
  462 Myrtle Avenue; 4 Fourth Avenue; 195 Montague Street
- Rubinson, Samuel J., 1904
  Glass dealer. 864 Myrtle Avenue
- Rueger, J. & Co., 1870
  Extension table maker. 181 Canal St.
- Rueger, John, 1890
  Carpenter and builder. 250 to 262 Moore St.
- Ruether, Henry C., 1883
  Grocer. 334 South 4th, cor. 10th Sts.
- Ruge, John F., 1891
  Metal worker. 50 Grand Street
- Ruppert, Joseph, 1914
  Iron & steel. 212 & 214 Duffield St. and 100-104 Willoughby St.
- Rush, Frank H., 1896
  Carpenter and builder. 327 Franklin Ave., near Greene Ave.
- Rush, Myron C., 1881
  Carpenter and builder. 329 Franklin Avenue, near Greene Ave.
- Rushmore, Isaac W., 1867, 1877
  Dealer in milk and butter. 100, 120 Atlantic Street, near Henry
- Russell, Louis, 1870
  Undertaker. Franklin St., Greenpoint